# John Teckemeyer

Full Stack Web Developer

Brentwood, California (510) 673-8723 johnteckemeyer@gmail.com github.com/TheTeck linkedin.com/in/john-teckemeyer

#### **SUMMARY**

I first started programming in high school over twenty years ago. Though my college career took a turn for another passion of mine, music, I have never lost the joy I had for programming. Now I have decided to leave my comfortable job of seventeen years to finally pursue this passion of mine and had recently enrolled and graduated from a boot camp for full stack web development. I am excited and looking forward to being a part of a team of like-minded people and getting to use my skills to help build amazing technologies.

#### **SKILLS**

**Python HTML** <u>Javascript</u> **NodeJS CSS** React **Django ExpressJS MongoDB PostgreSQL** AWS S3 **MongoDB Atlas VSCode** Git/Github **OAuth** JWT Auth

#### **PROJECTS**

## **EduSpark**

An online space for teachers and parents to communicate about students and their progress in class

- Effectively communicated with UX team and translated their vision into a usable application
- Wrote Class model schema and entire pipeline for its CRUD operations
- As per the design from the UX team, I developed the dashboard for the teachers on the frontend

#### **Sheet Music Maker**

An online sheet music editor with a social networking aspects that allows users to share their work and view other uses' works as well

- Frontend developed using React, Javascript, CSS and Semantic UI
- Backend developed with Node, Express and MongoDB/Mongoose
- Provided user security through JWT authentication
- Created a sheet music editor GUI using only React and CSS

## **Our Alley**

An online networking app that allows users to create playdates for their dogs. Using the Google Maps API, users can locate nearby dogs that are in the database

- Backend developed with Python, Django and a PostgreSQL database
- As scrum master, I defined and organized the particular tasks needed for our team to achieve our goals and effectively distributed duties.
- A major focus of mine in this project was to implement the functionality to geocode locations to locate other users within a certain radius of the current user using Google Maps API.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Teckemeyer Luthiery,** Brentwood, CA – *Owner/Luthier*

September 2017 - Present

Handcrafted high-quality classical guitars for clients. This being a one man business, I handled every aspect of running a business on top of developing my craft to significantly improve my product on each iteration.

## **Trader Joe's,** Brentwood, CA – *Section Leader*

April 2004 – January 2021

Managed multiple departments and provided superior customer service.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **General Assembly, Remote** – *Software Engineering*

February 2021 - May 2021

12-week training program, full-time, 500+ hours, project-based program taught by industry leaders.

## CSU East Bay, Hayward, CA – Music Composition

September 2002 - June 2008

Music theory, orchestration and multiple musical instrument performance taught by world-renowned musicians.